<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Lucas Pauker</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1311/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Lucas Pauker</description>
    <image>
      <title>Lucas Pauker</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1311/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1311/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1311/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why do Musical Scales Have Certain Numbers of Notes?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1311/articles/why-do-musical-scales-have-certain-numbers-of-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1311/articles/why-do-musical-scales-have-certain-numbers-of-notes/</guid>
      <description>The Question I, like many others, started learning to play piano when I was around 8 years old. I took lessons, learned songs, and gained an appreciation for the instrument. I have been playing (with some breaks) until today. Although I have been playing for a while, it wasn’t until taking my first music theory class in college that I started thinking deeply about why music is constructed in the way it is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classical Music Classifier Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1311/articles/music-matcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1311/articles/music-matcher/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This project done for my CS221 class aims to classify classical music by musical era (Baroque, Classical, Romantic, Modern) with composers as a proxy.
Using audio processing techniques, such as Short-time Fourier Transform, we extracted features such as the spectrogram and chromagram of the audio data from two datasets, Free Music Archive and MAESTRO.
We used two ensemble classifiers, AdaBoost and Random Forest, and found that although Adaboost performed marginally better than Random Forest, the latter made more generalizable predictions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
